Guide to the Blake Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Blake family papers
1773-1921
MS 85
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
10
(23 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, financial papers, printed material, photographs, and miscellanea of the Blake family of New Haven, Connecticut. Several generations of family members are represented in the papers, including Eli Whitney, Eli Whitney Blake (1795-1886), Eli Whitney Blake (1836-1895), Henry Taylor Blake (1828-1922), and William Phipps Blake (1826-). Additional family members represented in the papers include: Charles Thompson Blake, Edward Foster Blake, James Pierrepont Blake, Dotha Bushnell, George Bushnell, George Ensign Bushnell, Mary Elizabeth Bushnell, and members of the Hazard, MacWhorter, Osborne, and Rice families.
Blake family
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Thomas W. Hazard, 1946-1950.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged as follows: I. General Correspondence, 1773-1920. II. Family Correspondence, 1792-1921. III. Personal Papers, 1780-1920.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, financial papers, printed material, photographs, and miscellanea of the Blake family of New Haven, Connecticut. Several generations of family members are represented in the papers, including Eli Whitney, Eli Whitney Blake (1795-1886), Eli Whitney Blake (1836-1895), Henry Taylor Blake (1828-1922), and William Phipps Blake (1826-). Additional family members represented in the papers include: Charles Thompson Blake, Edward Foster Blake, James Pierrepont Blake, Dotha Bushnell, George Bushnell, George Ensign Bushnell, Mary Elizabeth Bushnell, and members of the Hazard, MacWhorter, Osborne, and Rice families.
Topics discussed in these papers include a wide variety of personal and family-related concerns, the estates of several family members, including Eli Whitney, and the professional careers of many of the above-named individuals. The scientific and inventing pursuits of Eli Whitney Blake (1795-1896), the academic career of physicist Eli Whitney Blake (1826-1895), the geological and mineralogical interests of William Phipps Blake are documented, as are the legal and political activites of Henry Taylor Blake, the hand craft industry operated by Dotha Bushnell, and the Civil War duties of Edward Foster Blake.
SERIES I, GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE, 1773-1920, contains letters in which only one of the correspondents is identified as a member of the Blake family. These letters do contain significant information on members of the Blake family and their activities, however. Among the correspondents included in this series are: members of the Adams, Bacon, Baldwin, Beecher, Belden, Burgess, Bushnell, Fairchild, Gilman, Henshaw, Merrill, Rice, Seely, Trumbull and Whitney families, and such individuals as Eliza Beers, Horace Bushnell, John J. Crittenden, Timothy Dwight, Edgar L. Heermance, Charles L. Ives, George B. MacLellan, Samuel B. Munson, and Increase N. Tarbox.
SERIES II, FAMILY CORRESPONDENCE, 1792-1921, contains letters exchanged between members of the extended Blake family. The letters are arranged alphabetically by the name of the author. For each author correspondence is organized alphabetically by the name of the correspondent. Thus, Charles Thompson Blake's letters to his father, Eli Whitney Blake are found under the former's name (box 8, folder 198), while Eli Whitney Blake's letters to his son Charles are found under the elder Blake's name (box 9, folder 223). Several generations and branches of the Blake family are represented in the series, including many of the female members.
The correspondence (and related papers) of Eli Whitney (box 19, folders 401-408) includes letters to his nephew, Eli Whitney Blake, and to his brother Josiah Whitney. Two financial accounts of cotton gin sales are also included (1807; 1824). Letters written to Eli Whitney Blake focus on the latter's impending education at Yale College (1811-1814), although later correspondence (1817-1819) includes a discussion of a hydrolic powered syphon for a water fountain
Correspondence to Josiah Whitney (1792-1823.) details Eli Whitney's interest and concern in family affairs and provides information on his business pursuits, including travels to the South in the early 1800's. The development and sale of the cotton gin are discussed, as are the political consequences of the Embargo Act and the War of 1812. Whitney was in Washington, D.C. in 1892, and his comments on the activities of Congress are those of a close observer. Personal and financial commentary continues through the year 1816. Correspondence from 1817-1819 is absent, although letters from 1820-1823 continue the regular exchange of letters between the brothers.
SERIES III, PERSONAL PAPERS, 1780-1920, contains a variety of account books, scrapbooks, sermons, notebooks, and miscellanea of family members and other individuals.Select files contains material arranged by the individual author/compiler.Topical files contain material not attributed to an individual.Select files include a notebook identified as that of Caleb Cushing. The volume contains clippings and data relating to the presidential election of 1864. Items relating to Edward Foster Blake include a published "Synopsis of Chemical Lectures in Yale College," (ca. 1856) and a "Colloquy for the Wooden Spoon," (August, 1852).Topical files include a small quantity of estate records, photographs, and obituaries for family members.
Biographical / Historical
ELI WHITNEY BLAKE, 1795-1886
Eli Whitney Blake was born in Westboro, Massachusetts on January 27, 1795. He graduated from Yale in 1816 and assisted his uncle, Eli Whitney, in the operation of a gun factory in New Haven, Connecticut. Blake continued the business after Whitney's death. In 1858 he invented the Blake crusher, a machine which broke stone into gravel. Blake wrote scientific papers and received an honorary degree (LL.D.) from Yale in 1875. He died in New Haven, Connecticut on August 18, 1886.
ELI WHITNEY BLAKE, 1836-1895
Eli Whitney Blake was born in New Haven, Connecticut on April 20, 1836. He graduated from Yale College in 1857. He served as professor of chemistry at the University of Vermont (1867), professor of physics at Cornell University (1868-1870), acting professor of physics at Columbia (1868-1869), and professor of physics at Brown University (1870-1886).
WILLIAM PHIPPS BLAKE, 1826
William Phipps Blake was born in New York City on June 1, 1826. He received the degree of Ph.B. from Yale in 1852. He served as geologist and mineralogist for a U.S. Pacific railroad expedition and became a professor of mineralogy and geology.
HENRY TAYLOR BLAKE, 1828-1922
Henry Taylor Blake was born in New Haven, Connecticut on April 27, 1828. He graduated from Yale in 1848 (A.B.) and studied at the Yale Law School. He practiced law in Bridgeport, Connecticut from 1850-1885. He returned to New Haven in 1885 and served on many municipal organizations until his death on April 6, 1922.
African Americans; Arts and crafts movement; Business; Businesswomen; Clergy; Cost and standard of living; Cotton gins and ginning; Families; Geology -- Alaska; Industries -- Connecticut -- New Haven; Science; Alaska -- History -- To 1867; Connecticut; Middle West; New England; New Haven (Conn.); New Haven (Conn.) -- Social life and customs; Peace Dale (R.I.); United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; West (U.S.); Alden, John A.; Atkinson, G. H. (George Henry), 1819-1889; Bacon, Helen Hazard, 1862-1925; Baldwin, Simeon E. (Simeon Eben), 1840-1927; Barbour, Caroline P.; Barstow, Elizabeth Fay Blake, 1792-1869; Barstow, Josiah Whitney, 1826-; Barstow, Z. S. (Zedekiah Smith), 1790-1873; Blake, Charles Thompson, 1826-1897; Blake, Edward Foster, 1837-1862; Blake, Edward Spencer, 1811-1881; Blake, Eli W. (Eli Whitney), 1795-1886; Blake, Eli Whitney, 1836-1895; Blake, Eli Whitney, 1867-1902; Blake, Elihu, 1764-1849; Blake, Elihu, 1793-; Blake, Eliza Maria O'Brien, 1799-1876; Blake, Elizabeth Coit Kingsley, 1830-1914; Blake, Elizabeth E. Vernon; Blake, George A., -1882; Blake, George W., 1808-1844; Blake, Harriet M. Rood, -1869; Blake, Harriet Waters Stiles; Blake, Henry T. (Henry Taylor), 1828-1922; Blake, Isabel; Blake, James Pierrepont, 1839-1865; Blake, John Adams; Blake, Josiah Whitney; Blake, Maria Georgianna; Blake, Maria Louisa; Blake, Philos, 1791-; Blake, William P. (William Phipps), 1826-1910; Bliss, Isaac G. (Isaac Grout), 1822-1889; Brace, Henry Martyn, 1828-1901; Bushnell, Adra V. Holmes, -1896; Bushnell, Dotha, 1861-1921; Bushnell, Ethel Maitland Barnard; Bushnell, Frances Louisa; Bushnell, George E. (George Ensign), 1853-1924; Bushnell, George, 1818-1898; Bushnell, Horace, 1802-1876; Bushnell, Mary Apthorp; Bushnell, Mary Elizabeth Blake, 1823-1916; Champlin, Carrie B.; Cheney, Mary Bushnell, 1840-1917; Dickinson, L. S.; Eaton, Daniel Cady, 1834-1895; Ellsworth, Catharine C. Smith; Fisher, Margaret Hazard, -1940; Foote, Amelia Stiles Leavitt Jenkins, 1799-1867; Foster, Harriet Smith, 1815-1893; Gilman, Daniel C. (Daniel Coit), 1831-1908; Gould, William Tracy, 1799-1882; Hazard, Ada Blake; Hazard, Caroline, 1856-1945; Hazard, Margaret Anna Rood, 1834-1895; Hazard, Mary Pierrepont Bushnell, 1859-1936; Hazard, Rowland Gibson, 1855-1918; Hazard, Rowland, 1829-1898; Henshaw, Sarah Edwards, 1822-1894; Vandegrift, Margaret, 1845-1913; Langdon, Abigail Pierrepont, 1797-; Leavitt, Mary H., 1798-; McWhorter Henrietta Whitney Blake, 1825-1901; Merrill, Eliza Skinner Bushnell, 1857-1919; Merrill, Robert T.; O'Brien, Henry Edward, 1797-1822; Orcutt, Fannie Louisa Blake; Orcutt, John, 1807-1879; Osborn, Fannie Louisa Blake, 1835-1893; Preston, H. W. (Harriet Waters), 1836-1911; Rice, Eliza Blake Seely, 1841-; Rice, Eliza Maria O'Brien; Rice, John Pierrepont, 1879-1941; Rice, John; Seely, Edward Blake, 1863-; Simpson, Helen; Smith, Emma J. Dickinson; Smith, Mary Elizabeth Bushnell Brookes, 1882-; Stevens, Eugene Rolaz, 1837-1905; Stevenson, Hannah E.; Taylor, Henry Wyllys, 1796-1888; Tomlinson, Charles, 1837-1921; Trow, George William, 1837-1872; Trumbull, David, 1819-1889; Trumbull, Jane Wales Fitch; Tyler, Edwin, 1827-1868; Wannamaker, Katharine Hume; Wannamaker, Olin D.; Whitney, Eli, 1740-1807; Whitney, Eli, 1765-1825; Whitney, Eli, 1820-1895; Whitney, Henrietta Frances Edwards; Woodward, Jane F.; Electric Purifier Company; Hillhouse High School (New Haven, Conn.); Hopkins Grammar School; Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1891; Yale University -- Students
- Correspondence, 1773-1920; Series I; 3; (7 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence arranged in alphabetical order. Letters to family members whose last name is "Blake" are arranged in box seven.
  - Adams family, 1830-1900 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ainslie family, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alden family, 1867-1880 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Allen, Elizabet, 1876-1892 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - American Exchange National Bank, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Armstrong, M., 1866 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Atkinson, George, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ayers, C., 1836 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - B (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bacon, Helen, 1880-1886 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bacon family, 1839-1862 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Balch, Katharine T., 1919 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Baldwin family, 1854-1866 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Barbour, Caroline P., 1858-1892 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Barnett, Mary W., undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Barstow, Elizabeth Fay, 1844-1866 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Barstow, Josiah W. and Zedekiah S., 1860-1882 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Beecher family, 1860-1882 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Beers, Eliza, 1812 June 17 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Belden family, 1895-1897 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bellow, F., 1889 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Benson, Fannie H., 1874 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Berrien, John MacPherson, 1820 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bliss, Eunice (Day), 1858-1860 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bliss, Isaac Grout, 1858-1861 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Booth family, 1837-1880 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Brace family, 1847-1850 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Brookes family, 1903-1913 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Burgess family, 1847 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Bushnell, Adra V., 1881-1890 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Bushnell, Horace, 1849-1870 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Bushnell family, 1852-1921 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Bushnell family, 1802-1884 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - C (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Campbell, Mary and Wallace, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Carmalt, Ethel, 1906-1921 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Chamberlain, Daniel, 1866-1876 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Champlin, Carrie B., 1856-1859 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Cheney family, 1865-1900 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Child, Francis J., 1865 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Collie, J., 1884 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Colt, William U., 1842-1843 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Crawford family, 1862-1872 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Crittendon, John J., 1847 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Crosby, James H., 1867 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Curtis, G., 1800 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - D (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Deutsch family, 1864-1866 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Dickinson, L., 1867-1869 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Dixon, J., undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Dutton family, 1857-1865 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Dwight, Timothy, 1862-1898 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - E - F - G (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Eaton family, 1860-1885 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Eddy, G., undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Edwards, Amory, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Eichelberger, Martin S., 1858-1859 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Ellsworth, Catharine C., 1816-1823 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Fairbanks, Arthus, 1897 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Fairchild family, 1872 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Fairfax, Wilson, 1831 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Fisher, Margaret H., 1874 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Flipper, Henry O., 1874 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Foote family, 1815-1822, 1859 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Foster family, 1803-1903 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Gibbons, Charles, 1862-1863 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Gilman family, 1857-1862 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Goddard family, 1816-1903 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Goodall, M., 1885 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Gough, John B., 1860 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Gould, William T., 1871-1881 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Grinnell, Eliza S., 1814 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - H - L (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Harmar, James L., 1866 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Harrison, C., 1865 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Hatch, Walter, 1881 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Hayden, Anne, 1902 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Heermance, Edgar L., 1860 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Henshaw family, 1860-1888 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Hicks, Dr. Bonaparte, 1840 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Hill, L., undated (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Hinckley, Henry Rose, 1860-1862 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Hollister, Arthur N., undated (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Howland, J., 1875 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Hubbard, I., undated (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Hume, Edward H., 1903 (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Ives, Charles L., 1863 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Janvier family, 1872-1897 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Kean, Katherine W., undated (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Kempton, Lydia D., 1876 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Kenyon family, 1898-1920 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Kingsbury, Alla R., undated (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Langdon, Abigail, 1814-1822 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Larned, Sophy, 1849 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Larvire, George, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Leavitt family, 1815-1819 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Lechler, John W., 1912 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - M (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - McKim, Lucy, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - MacLellan, George B., 1858 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Margden family, 1872-1874 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Martindale, H., undated (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Marvin, Edwin E., 1865 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Meary, John W., 1849 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Merrill family, 1865-1920 (Box 3, Folder 106-107)
  - Metropolitan Trust Co., 1903 (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Mills, Harriet A., 1895 (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - Mitchell, Donald G., undated (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - Moulton, Elizabeth A., 1918 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - Munson, Samuel B., 1875-1880 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Murray, David, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - New Haven Union Association, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Newton, Miss Clifford, 1896 (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - New York National Park Bank, 1868 (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - O'Brien, Henry E., 1812-1820 (Box 4, Folder 117-118)
  - Olcott, Charles, 1856 (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - Olmsted, M., 1831 (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - Orcutt, Fanny Louisa, 1845-1891 (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Orcutt, John, 1860-1877 (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - Osborne, Elizabeth Annah, undated (Box 4, Folder 123)
  - Palmer, Charles T.H., 1847 (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Parkman, John, 1869 (Box 4, Folder 125)
  - Pease, Thomas Huntington, 1865 (Box 4, Folder 126)
  - Peck, A., 1881 (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - Peirce, Luther Hills, 1857-1858 (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Perkins, Thomas Albert, 1859-1860 (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Phinney, Elihu, 1875-1876 (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Pierpont family, 1773 (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Pierson, R., undated (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - Pitkin, Walter Stanley, 1837-1858 (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - Plant, J., 1870 (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - Pond, M., 1869 (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Pater family, 1873-1885 (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Preston, Harriet W., 1903-1910 (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Quimby, David, 1877 (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - R____, Lucy, undated (Box 4, Folder 139)
  - Randle, N., 1862 (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - Renville, Mary A., undated (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Rice family, 1874-1920 (Box 4, Folder 142-143)
  - Riggs, S., 1869 (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - Riley, Isaac, 1856-1858 (Box 4, Folder 145)
  - Robinson family, 1858-1900 (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - Rumsey, Maria, 1849 (Box 5, Folder 147)
  - S - T (Box 5, Folder 148)
  - Sabieskie, M., 1849 (Box 5, Folder 149)
  - Salem St. Congregational Church Worcester, Mass, 1858 (Box 5, Folder 150)
  - Scranton, Charles W., 1902 (Box 5, Folder 151)
  - Seely family, 1849-1902 (Box 5, Folder 152)
  - Shaw, Maria J., 1903 (Box 5, Folder 153)
  - Shepard, C., 1865-1866 (Box 5, Folder 154)
  - Simpson family, 1859-1863 (Box 5, Folder 155)
  - Smith family, 1816-1905 (Box 5, Folder 156)
  - Stevens, Eugene R., 1855-1859 (Box 5, Folder 157)
  - Stevenson, Hannah E., 1864-1865 (Box 5, Folder 158)
  - Stoddard, Frances E., 1884 (Box 5, Folder 159)
  - Strong, Augustus Hopkins, 1859-1860 (Box 5, Folder 160)
  - Sturges, Elizabeth, 1895-1903 (Box 5, Folder 161)
  - Taggart, A., undated (Box 5, Folder 162)
  - Tarbox, Increase N., 1879 (Box 5, Folder 163)
  - Taylor family, 1861-1885 (Box 5, Folder 164)
  - Thacher family, 1884-1906 (Box 5, Folder 165)
  - Tomlinson, Charles, 1857-1865 (Box 5, Folder 166)
  - Trow, George Wm., 1859-1860 (Box 5, Folder 167)
  - Trumbull family, 1853-1889 (Box 5, Folder 168)
  - Twombly, W., 1859 (Box 5, Folder 169)
  - Tyler family, 1847-1868 (Box 5, Folder 170)
  - Vernon, Anna, undated (Box 5, Folder 171)
  - Vose, George F., 1860 (Box 5, Folder 172)
  - W (Box 5, Folder 173)
  - Walker family, 1881-1890 (Box 5, Folder 174)
  - Wannamaker family, 1894-1919 (Box 5, Folder 175)
  - Ward, Henry D., 1819-1842 (Box 5, Folder 176)
  - Welch M., 1864 (Box 6, Folder 177)
  - White family, 1836-1855 (Box 6, Folder 178)
  - Whiting, John H., 1883 (Box 6, Folder 179)
  - Whitney family, 1830-1897 (Box 6, Folder 180)
  - Williams, Isabella B., 1866-1871 (Box 6, Folder 181)
  - Williamson, John P., 1869 (Box 6, Folder 182)
  - Whipple, Dotha, undated (Box 6, Folder 183)
  - Woodward, Jane, 1848-1903 (Box 6, Folder 184)
  - Woolsey, Sarah, undated (Box 6, Folder 185)
  - Yale University Olympia Boat Club, 1859 (Box 6, Folder 186)
  - Blake, Adeline - Edward, 1836-1908 (Box 7, Folder 187)
  - Blake, Edward Spencer - Eli Whitney, 1835-1902 (Box 7, Folder 188)
  - Blake, Eli Whitney - Elihu, Jr., 1829-1874 (Box 7, Folder 189)
  - Blake, Elizabeth B. - Elizabeth E., 1844-1900 (Box 7, Folder 190)
  - Blake, Elizabeth E. - Harriet Waters, 1860-1890 (Box 7, Folder 191)
  - Blake, Harriet Waters, 1870-1904 (Box 7, Folder 192)
  - Blake, Harriet Waters - Isabel, 1864-1919 (Box 7, Folder 193)
  - Blake, Isabel, 1864-1903 (Box 7, Folder 194)
  - Blake, John Adams - Josiah Whitney, 1828-1881 (Box 7, Folder 195)
  - Blake, Maria Georgianna - Philos, 1801-1820 (Box 7, Folder 196)
  - Blake, Maria Louisa - William Phipps, 1847-1882 (Box 7, Folder 197)
- Family correspondence, 1792-1921; Series II; 5; (12 boxes)
  This series contains correspondence arranged in alphabetical order the names of individuals who wrote the letters. Each individual's correspondence is arranged alphabetical by the recipient of the letter(s).
  - Select
    - Blake, Charles Thompson
      - Blake, Eli Whitney, 1863-1884 (Box 8, Folder 198)
      - Blake, Eliza, 1839-1868 (Box 8, Folder 199)
      - Blake, Henry T., 1857-1897 (Box 8, Folder 200)
      - Bushnell, Mary E., 1848-1897 (Box 8, Folder 201-202)
      - McWhorter, Henrietta, 1840-1884 (Box 8, Folder 203)
    - Blake, Edward Foster
      - Blake, Eli Whitney, 1859-1862 (Box 8, Folder 204)
      - Blake, Eliza M., 1857-1862 (Box 8, Folder 205)
        - Oversize (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Blake, George A., 1851-1862 (Box 8, Folder 206)
        - Oversize (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Blake, James P., 1861-1862 (Box 8, Folder 207)
      - Osborne, Fanny L., 1847-1862 (Box 8, Folder 208)
      - R____, H., 1861 (Box 8, Folder 209)
      - Miscellaneous papers and transcripts, 1837-1862 (Box 8, Folder 210-216)
      - Miscellaneous papers and transcripts, 1860-1863 (Box 9, Folder 217-221)
    - Blake, Eli Whitney
      - Barstow, Elizabeth F., 1811-1848 (Box 9, Folder 222)
      - Blake, Charles T., 1858-1885 (Box 9, Folder 223)
      - Blake, Edward F., 1848-1880 (Box 9, Folder 224)
      - Blake, Elihu, Jr., 1809-1863 (Box 9, Folder 225)
      - Blake, Eliza M., 1843-1866 (Box 9, Folder 226)
      - Bushnell, Mary E., 1865-1884 (Box 9, Folder 227)
      - Unidentified, 1831-1879 (Box 9, Folder 228)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1821-1823 (Box 9, Folder 229)
    - Blake, Eli Whitney, Jr.
      - Blake, Edward F., 1848-1880 (Box 10, Folder 230)
      - Blake, Eli Whitney, 1853-1889 (Box 10, Folder 231)
      - Bushnell, Mary E., 1853-1881 (Box 10, Folder 232)
    - Blake, Eliza Maria
      - Blake, James P., 1864-1865 (Box 10, Folder 233)
      - Bushnell, Mary E., 1835-1865 (Box 10, Folder 234)
    - Blake, George A.
      - Blake, Eli Whitney, 1861-1881 (Box 10, Folder 235)
      - Blake, Eliza M., 1835-1882 (Box 10, Folder 236)
      - Blake, Henry Taylor, 1880-1881 (Box 10, Folder 237)
      - Bushnell, George E., 1865-1874 (Box 10, Folder 238)
      - Bushnell, Mary E., 1865-1879 (Box 10, Folder 239-240)
    - Blake, Henry Taylor
      - Blake, Eli Whitney, undated (Box 10, Folder 241)
      - Blake, Eliza M., 1840-1882 (Box 10, Folder 242)
      - Bushnell, Dotha, 1855-1918 (Box 10, Folder 243)
      - Bushnell, Mary E., 1851-1885 (Box 10, Folder 244)
      - MacWhorter, Henrietta, 1839-1890 (Box 10, Folder 245)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1862-1881 (Box 11, Folder 246-248)
    - Blake, James Pierrepont
      - Blake, Eliza, 1842-1865 (Box 11, Folder 249)
      - Crosby, James H., 1862-1865 (Box 11, Folder 250)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 11, Folder 251-252)
    - Blake, William Phipps: notes and papers, 1860-1863 (Box 11, Folder 253-257)
    - Bushnell, Dotha
      - A-E (Box 11, Folder 258-261)
      - C-W (Box 12, Folder 262-268)
      - Blake, Eli Whitney, 1849-1916 (Box 12, Folder 269)
      - Bushnell, George, 1870-1916 (Box 12, Folder 270)
      - Bushnell, Mary E., 1876-1897 (Box 12, Folder 271)
    - Bushnell, George
      - Bushnell, George Ensign, 1851-1890 (Box 12, Folder 272)
      - Bushnell, Mary E., 1862-1876 (Box 12, Folder 273-275)
    - Bushnell, George Ensign
      - Blake, Eli Whitney, 1865-1883 (Box 12, Folder 276)
      - Bushnell, Dotha, 1877-1921 (Box 12, Folder 277)